Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/shaquilleoneal (LinkedIn) shaq.com/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Account Management
Advertising
Basketball

Shaquille O'Neal

Business mogul, Former athlete, Purveyor of fun Windermere

Summary

During 19 seasons in the National Basketball League, I drove success on and off the court. I developed partnerships with global brands, pursued my academic interests in business and leadership and became the only current or former NBA player to hold three degrees: a bachelor's, a master's and a doctorate.

Basketball remains a big part of my life, whether it is providing NBA analysis on TV, serving as part-owner of the Sacramento Kings or appearing as a featured character in the latest video games. Since 1985, every NBA championship team has included a current or former teammate. I guess that makes me the Kevin Bacon of basketball.

Since retiring from the basketball court, I've expanded my brand relationships into one of the most diverse portfolios in the business world. As an early adopter of technology, I've identified innovative organizations as a serial tech investor. I work with brands that are household names such as Turner Networks, Reebok, IcyHot, AT&T and many other great companies. I also bring my business acumen to like-minded companies as a featured speaker at conferences and events nationwide.

Though I'm best known for basketball and business, my interests have always varied. I've released four studio albums and served as a sworn reserve officer in several law enforcement agencies across the country. I've collaborated on everything from fashion lines and jewelry to best-selling beverages and foods; from the latest technology products and games to children's books.

Experience

Turner Family of Networks
NBA Analyst
October 2011 - Present (8 years 11 months)
Page 1 of 5

Co-Host of the seven-time Emmy-award-winning "Inside the NBA" on TNT.

Star and Executive Producer on Turner Productions, including "Upload with Shaquille O'Neal" on Tru TV, "Hall of Game Awards" on Cartoon Network, and NBA TV.

Icy Hot

Brand Ambassador

March 2003 - Present (17 years 6 months)

Represented the brand for more than 10 years, starring in nationwide advertisements that boosted the product from third place to the top seller in its category.

AT&T

Brand Ambassador

March 2015 - Present (5 years 6 months)

Star of commercials aired during 2015 NCAA March Madness.

Zyloware Eyewear

Collection Partner

February 2015 - Present (5 years 7 months)

Collaborated on an exclusive line of Shaq-branded eyewear, available in stores nationwide winter 2015-2016.

Bloomsbury Publishing

Creative Partner

January 2015 - Present (5 years 8 months)

Teamed up on "Little Shaq," my first children's book, on shelves in stores fall 2015.

PLAYSTUDIOS

Licensing Partner

November 2014 - Present (5 years 10 months)

Featured star of mobile games, CaddyShaq and ShaqJack, allowing players to earn real life rewards for on-screen wins. Available on Facebook, Kindle, Android and iOS.

Accessory Innovations

Collection Partner

September 2014 - Present (6 years)

Created an exclusive line of accessories, including backpacks and hats, available at national retailers.

Post Foods

Brand Ambassador

August 2014 - Present (6 years 1 month)

Featured in Fruity Pebbles advertisements and on product boxes in 10,000 retailers nationwide, with more than 11 million boxes sold to date.

Anheuser-Busch China

Brand Ambassador

July 2014 - Present (6 years 2 months)

Star of two commercials for Anheuser-Busch beverages, airing nationwide in China.

PVH Corp.

Collection Partner

May 2014 - Present (6 years 4 months)

Exclusive collection of dress shirts and ties in all sizes, available at Macy's.

NBA 2K

Featured Character

May 2014 - Present (6 years 4 months)

Featured as half-time show analyst and NBA star in the video game, available for XBOX, PlayStation, PC and as a mobile app.

Monster Inc.

Licensing Partner

April 2014 - Present (6 years 5 months)

Featured in commercials and on brand packaging of Monster's Powercard portable phone charger and Superstar Bluetooth speaker.

Berkshire Fashions

Collection Partner

January 2014 - Present (6 years 8 months)

Exclusive line of cold weather gear, including outerwear, gloves, beanies and more, available at national retailers.

Zales

Collection Partner

April 2013 - Present (7 years 5 months)

The Shaquille O'Neal collection offers an exclusive line of stainless steel men's jewelry. Originally offered in 400 Zales locations, the collection expanded to 600 stores nationwide in fall 2014.

Reebok

Licensing Partner

February 2013 - Present (7 years 7 months)

Recharging our 20-plus year relationship, we teamed up in 2013 to bring Shaq Attaq and Shaqnosis shoes to stores nationwide.

AriZona Beverage Co.

Licensing Partner

January 2013 - Present (7 years 8 months)

The face of Shaq Fu Punch and Soda Shaq, the latter of which had the most successful beverage launch in brand history, with more than 50 million cans sold in its first year.

Peerless Clothing Inc.

Collection Partner

January 2013 - Present (7 years 8 months)

Launched in January 2014, the Shaquille O'Neal Collection includes jackets, sport coats, suits and pants in all sizes sold exclusively at Macy's.

Gold Bond

Brand Ambassador

January 2012 - Present (8 years 8 months)

Since 2012, represented the brand in nationwide advertisements. The product has gone from fifth-best lotion to a category leader.

Grand Central Publishing

Author

November 2011 - Present (8 years 10 months)

Featured on The New York Times bestseller list, author of autobiography "Shaq Uncut," written in collaboration with veteran sports writer Jackie MacMullan of ESPN and formerly, The Boston Globe.

ACI International

Licensing Partner

January 2010 - Present (10 years 8 months)

More than 100 million pairs of Shaq brand/Dunkman shoes sold worldwide at retail partners, including Walmart, Big 5 Sporting Goods and JCPenney.

National Basketball Association Professional Basketball Player 1992 - 2011 (19 years)

Drafted in 1992 as the #1 draft pick to the Orlando Magic. Awarded Rookie of the Year. During a 19-year career, proudly wore the jersey of six NBA franchises. On the Los Angeles Lakers, won three consecutive NBA Championships from 2000-2002. Won a fourth with the Miami Heat in 2006. Named MVP in three NBA finals, once for the whole league and a two-time NBA scoring champion. Participated in 15 NBA All Star games.

Education

LSU

Bachelor's degree, Business Administration · (1989 - 1992)

University of Phoenix

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Business Administration and Management, General · (2002 - 2006)

Barry University

Doctor of Education (Ed.D.) · (2007 - 2013)